A Guide to the Margaret Burroughs Aull Papers, 1883-2006 (bulk 1985-2005)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Margaret Burroughs Aull Papers, 1883-2006 (bulk 1985-2005)
The Library of Virginia
42691
12 cubic feet (27 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Margaret Burroughs Aull, Amarillo, Texas.
Biographical Information
Margaret Ann Burroughs was born in Bedford, Taylor County, Iowa on 14 January 1918. She was the daughter of Rev. Ursa Earl Burroughs (1882-1969) and Vera Alice Parker (1882-1960). She graduated from William Jewell College in Liberty, Missouri. She married George Frederick Aull (1914-2001) in Borger, Hutchinson County, Texas on 8 March 1940. Margaret Burroughs Aull taught high school English in Borger for 32 years. After retirement, she volunteered teaching English as a second language at Frank Phillips College, and she also wrote a newspaper column for the Borger News-Herald entitled "Aull's Well." Aull died in Lubbock, Texas on 19 March 2011, and is buried in New Hope Cemetery in Liberty, Missouri.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1883-2006, of Margaret Burroughs Aull (1918-2011) of Borger, Hutchinson County, Texas, containing genealogical research files on the Burroughs family, and the allied families of Aull, Bondurant, Booth, Cocke, Faure, Foose, Ford, Hayter, Hon, Maxey, Parker, Pierce, and Thaxton, including lines that settled in Amelia, Bedford, Buckingham, Franklin, Goochland, and Henrico Counties, Virginia, and Iowa, Illinois, Kentucky, Missouri, Ohio, and Texas. The collection also contains files related to her involvement in various hereditary and patriotic organizations.
The collection includes abstracts, copies, and transcriptions of Bible records, census records, deeds, land patents and grants, military records, parish registers, tax records, wills and other estate administration records, and published sources. There are also brochures and guidebooks, clippings, family group sheets, genealogical charts and pedigrees, maps, newsletters, obituaries, and photographs. There is also information on Aull's ancestor, James Burroughs (1794-1861) and his plantation, where Booker T. Washington (1856-1913) was born into slavery.
Much of Aull's research was used to apply for membership in various organizations, including the Daughters of the American Revolution, Huguenot Society of the Founders of Manakin in the Colony of Virginia, National Society Colonial Dames XVII Century, National Society Magna Charta Dames, and the United Daughters of the Confederacy. There are application papers, constitutions and bylaws, information on projects and programs organized by the groups, publications, and yearbooks.
Contents List
- Abbotts Ann. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Addresses. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Adventurers of Purse and Person. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ahnentafels. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amarillo Genealogical Society. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Americans of Royal Descent Membership. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ancestral Roots of Certain American Colonists by Frederick Lewis Weis. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Aull. (Box 1, Folder 9-13)
- Aull - Belleville, IL. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Aull, George Frederick - Funeral. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Aull in the Family by James C. Aull. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Aull, James C.. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Aull, Josie Hon - Contents of Cedar Chest. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Aull, Margaret B. - Teaching Career. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Aull's Well". (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Baptist (Northern Baptist Convention), vol. 1, no. 1, 13 January 1920. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Baptist General Convention of Texas - Top O' Texas Yearbook, 1969. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Batt. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bedford City/County Museum. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bedford Villages - Lost and Found (Volumes 1-3). (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Beefeater Distillery (Burrough, Norman). (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bible Record - Aull. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Bible Record - Burroughs. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Biblical Archaeology Review November/December 1998. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Bigod. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Birth Certificates. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Blandford Church Windows - UDC Program. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bondurant. (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
- Bondurant Family Association. (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
- Booth. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Booth/Boothe. (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- Booth-Tate. (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
- Brescoll, James. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- British Origins of American Colonists, 1629-1775 by WIlliam Dollarhide. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Brockman, William Everett. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Burrough, Rev. Jonathan (Acton, London). (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Burroughs. (Box 4, Folder 8-15)
- Burroughs. (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
- Burroughs. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Burroughs - Census. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Burroughs (Ruth and Frank Dillingham/Helen Fulmer). (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Burroughs, Elizabeth - Marriage Record. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Burroughs - England. (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
- Burroughs Family Group Sheets. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Burroughs Genealogy. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Burroughs (Sue Gorrence). (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Burroughs, James - Will, 1861. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Burroughs, James (Barry Mackintosh Book). (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Burroughs, John - Will, 1791. (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Burroughs, John Francis - Civil War Records. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Burroughs, John Francis - Obituary. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Burroughs, John Virgil - Obituary. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Burroughs, Mary - Estate Account, 1844. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Burroughs (Bonnie Early Meeks). (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
- Burroughs (Margaret Miles). (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
- Burroughs (Madelyn T. Payne). (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Burroughs, Peter. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Burroughs-Pierce. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Burroughs Plantation - Franklin County, VA. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- The Burroughs Plantation, 1856-1865 by Barry Mackintosh, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Burroughs (Bert Porter). (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Burroughs, Samuel Raymond. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Burroughs, Sarah - Will, 1839. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Burroughs (Tim Sudbrink). (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Burroughs, Thomas, Military Records. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Burroughs, Thomas - Will, 1879. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Burroughs, Ursa Earl. (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
- Burroughs, Ursa Earl - Wallet Contents. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Burroughs, Vera Alice Parker - Essays. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Burruss. (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Butler, Willard J.. (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Calendar, 1986. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- California - Brochures. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Cavaliers and Pioneers. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Census - Maryland, 1790. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Census - Missouri - Daviess County. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Census - Missouri - Saline County. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Census - Virginia, 1810. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Census - Virginia - Bedford County. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Census - Virginia - Bedford County, 1840. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Certificates. (Box PP Oversize Box 59, Folder n/a)
- Charts/Pedigrees. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Charts/Pedigrees (Oversize). (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Chastain. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Clippings. (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
- Coca-Cola. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Cocke. (Box 8, Folder 15-18)
- Cocke (Jeane Hull). (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Colonial Order of the Crown Membership. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- The Confederate Dead: Memorial Day at Elmwood Cemetery, Norfolk, Virginia, 18 June 1884. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1924-1969. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1970-1979. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1980-1985. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1986-1990. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1991-1995. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1996-1999. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Correspondence - Personal, 2000-2004. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Correspondence - Personal, undated. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Correspondence Log. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Cotten (Betty South). (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Crests. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Daughters of the American Revolution. (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - American History Month. (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Braille Flag Project. (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Bylaws (Josiah Bartlett Chapter). (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Constitution Week. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Flag Day. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Magazine, 1991, 1996-1999. (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Manual of Citizenship. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - New Ancestor Records (From Magazine). (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Star Spangled Banner. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - George Washington Bicentennial Community. (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Yearbooks. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Death Certificates. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Deciphering the Church Records of Germany by Beverly Boehl. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Delta Kappa Gamma. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- The Diligence and the Disappearance of Manakintowne's Huguenots by Allison Wehr Elterich. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- The Douglas Register. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Duck Creek Acres by Eleanor H. Percival. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Early Ohio Settlers. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Early Settlers of Maryland. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Embry. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- English Genealogy. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- English Origins of American Colonists. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- English Tourist Attractions - Notebook. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Ephemera. (Box 27, Folder n/a)
- Farrar. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Fauquier County, VA. (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Faure. (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
- Faure-Foard-Fore by Mary Ford Southworth, 1965. (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Faure/Ford. (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
- Faure/Ford Family Group Sheets. (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Faure Ford Fore Force of Manakin Town by Larry Ford. (Box 11, Folder 18)
- First Baptist Church. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Foose. (Box 12, Folder 2-8)
- Ford Data (Betty Leavell). (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Ford, Peter - Deeds. (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Ford, Peter - Inventory. (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Ford, Peter - Will, 1745. (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Ford, Peter - Will, 1798. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Fore Family Newsletter. (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Franklin County, VA. (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Franklin County, VA - Bicentennial Reflections. (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Friends of the Library - Notebook. (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Friends of St. George's Chapel. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Froebe, Verba P.. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- From Palatinate of the Rhine to South Carolina by Sara Aull. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Genealogy Class, 1988. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Genealogy Notebook, 1987. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Genealogy Notebook, 1988. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Genealogy Notebook, 1989. (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Genealogy Sources. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Gilliam. (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Golden Rule Packing Company (Thaxton, VA). (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
- Gould, Lo Raye Wood. (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
- Great Britain (Baedeker's Guidebook). (Box 14, Folder n/a)
- Greer. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Grundy County, MO. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Guest Register. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Guide to the Buildings of Surry and the American Revolution by James D. Kernwolf. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- The Handy Book for Genealogists. (Box 14, Folder n/a)
- Hanthorn, Ula Mae Maxey. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Hardy - England. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Helms, Virgil R.. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Highland County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 8)
- A History of Libraries in the Western World by Elmer D. Johnson. (Box 14, Folder 9)
- The Holy Land in Colour by Sami Awwad. (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Hon. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Hon-Hayter. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Hopkins of Virginia and Related Families by Walter Lee Hopkins. (Box 15, Folder 4)
- J.M Huber Corporation. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Huguenot Society. (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
- Huguenot Society Application Papers. (Box 15, Folder 8-12)
- Huguenot Society Newsletters. (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Huguenot Society Yearbook, 2001-2003. (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Huguenots. (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Hutchinson County Genealogical Society. (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Kentucky Research Sources. (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Kmoch, Chrystall. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Lineage of George Edward Boothe by Mary Edna Mitchell. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- A List of Emigrant Ministers to America by Gerald Fothergill. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Literacy. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Loudon Park Cemetery, Baltimore. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Madison County Kentucky Marriage Records Vol. 1, 1786-1822. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Magan Addition (Thaxton, VA) Survey - Blueprint 1840. (Box PP Oversize Box 59, Folder n/a)
- Magna Charta Dames and Barons. (Box 16, Folder 9-14)
- Magna Charta Dames and Barons Yearbooks, 1998-2006. (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Marriage Records. (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
- Maryland Calendar of Wills. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Maury, Matthew Fontaine - UDC Program. (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
- Maxey. (Box 17, Folder 6-12)
- Maxey (Betty Jean Cobb). (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Maxey, Edward - Will, 1740. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Maxey Family Group Sheets. (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
- Maxey (Gerald Maxey). (Box 18, Folder 5)
- The Maxey Messenger. (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Maxey (Carole Stowell). (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Maxey, Susannah - Will, 1743. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Maxey, William - Deeds. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- The Maxeys of Virginia by Edythe Maxey Clark. (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Maynes, Betty. (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
- Memorandum Books. (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Military Records - Civil War. (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Miller-Aull-Geilker House, Liberty, MO. (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Muskingum County Genealogical Society Newsletter, 1987. (Box 18, Folder 17)
- National Society Colonial Dames XVII Century. (Box 18, Folder 18-21)
- National Society Colonial Dames XVII Century - Directories and Yearbooks, 1999-2005. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- National Society Colonial Dames XVII Century - Handbook and National Bylaws, 1991. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- National Society Colonial Dames XVII Century - Seventeenth Century Review, 1999-2003. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Newsletters. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Newspapers (William Jewell College and Liberty, MO). (Box PP Oversize Box 59, Folder n/a)
- Obituaries. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Old Churches, Ministers, and Families of Virginia by Bishop William Meade. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Our Kin: The Genealogies of Some of the Early Families Who Made History in the Founding and Development of Bedford County (Annotated). (Box 19, Folder n/a)
- Parker. (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
- Parker - Cousins' Letters. (Box 20, Folder 4-9)
- Parker, Isaac (Judge) - Prologue Article. (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Parker, Rev. John Talton - Obituary. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Parker (Martha Johnson). (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Parker, Roy Hartford. (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Parker-Sullivan. (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Passports. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Paxton, Steven. (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Peaks of Otter. (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Penn, Gabriel - Will, 1798. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- The Perry Magazine, June 1903. (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Photo Album. (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Photographs - Aull/Neas/Springer. (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
- Photographs - Burroughs. (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
- Photographs - Faure/Ford. (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Photographs - Hon. (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Photographs - Maxey. (Box 21, Folder 13-14)
- Photographs - Parker. (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
- Photographs - Randall. (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Photographs - Slover. (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Photographs - Stubbs. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Photographs - Thaxton. (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Photographs - Cemeteries. (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Photographs - Miscellaneous. (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Photographs - Negatives. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Photographs - Unidentified. (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Photographs - Virginia Places. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Pittsylvania County, VA. (Box 22, Folder 9)
- A Place Called Poosey by Anna Dockery Burgess. (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Plaidy, Jean. (Box 22, Folder 11-12)
- Plantagenet Society Membership. (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Pocohontas by Stuart E. Brown, Jr.. (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Poetry/Verses/Songs. (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Prince William County, VA. (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Programs. (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Recipes. (Box 22, Folder 18)
- Reed, Redell T.. (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Research in Virginia by Robert Y. Clay, 1980. (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Rice, Lyman and Bertha. (Box 22, Folder 21)
- Road Maps. (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Salisbury Cathedral. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Scipes. (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Selborne. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Seventeenth Century Colonial Ancestors by Mary Louise Marshall Hutton. (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Shannon, Virginia. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Ship Passenger Lists. (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Some Emigrants to Virginia by W.G. Stanard. (Box 23, Folder 7)
- The Southern Literary Messenger, July-August 1943. (Box 23, Folder 8)
- The Southern Magazine, 1935-1936. (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Springer, Whitney Leigh - Mission Trip, 1999. (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Stephens. (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Stephens Family Group Sheets. (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Stone, Doris Y.. (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Stubbs. (Box 24, Folder 1)
- A Survey of American Church Records by E. Kay Kirkham. (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Sussex County, VA. (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Sympathy Cards and Letters - Death of Josie Hon Aull, 1971. (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Telephone Book - Bedford/Stone Mountain, 1984. (Box 24, Folder 5)
- 1066 And All That by W.C. Sellar and R.J. Yeatman. (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Tennessee - Maps. (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Thaxton. (Box 24, Folder 8-12)
- Thaxton, Abel. (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Thaxton-Burroughs. (Box 24, Folder 14-15)
- Thaxton, Emmett W.. (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Thaxton (Peggy Wood Lewis. (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
- Thaxton, Robert B. - Civil War Records. (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Thaxton (Jean Magann). (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Thaxton, VA - Newspaper Article. (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Tourist Brochures. (Box 25, Folder 6)
- A Touch of History - Botetourt County Historical Society, 1994-1996. (Box 25, Folder 7)
- United Confederate Veterans - Programs, 1883, 1906-1913. (Box 25, Folder 8)
- United Daughters of the Confederacy. (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
- United Daughters of the Confederacy - Addresses, Programs, etc., 1909-1921. (Box 25, Folder 11)
- United Daughters of the Confederacy - Constitutions and Bylaws. (Box 25, Folder 12)
- United Daughters of the Confederacy - Magazine, 1947, 1955. (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Videotape - Booth Family Search - Virginia (Aubrey, Ben and Jack), 17-18 April 1993. (Box 27, Folder n/a)
- Virginia Baptist Historical Society. (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Virginia County Formation. (Box 25, Folder 15)
- Virginia Genealogical Research by George K. Schweitzer. (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Virginia Wills and Administrations. (Box 25, Folder 17)
- War of 1812 - Pay Roll. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Washington, Booker T.. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Booker T. Washington National Monument. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- West Virginia. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Wickes, Michael. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- White House of the Confederacy. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Will of Margaret B. Aull, 1976. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- William Jewell College. (Box 26, Folder 8-9)
- Wood, Mary Frances. (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Writing, Literature, etc.. (Box 26, Folder 11)
- The Year Without a Summer by Henry and Elizabeth Stommel. (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Yeates, Barry R.. (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Your Family Tree by David Starr Jordan. (Box 26, Folder 14)